Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Detroit Office. Ford collateral literature, 1939-2007 and undated RL.11679
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Detroit Office. Ford collateral literature
1939-2007 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Detroit Office
RL.11679
50.0 Linear Feet
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. It is headquartered in New York. JWT maintained an office in Detroit from 1909-1920 and reopened it in 1944. Collection includes catalogs, direct mailings, newsletters and magazines, owner's manuals, posters, sales incentive and sales training materials, service manuals, technical bulletins and other printed materials. Competitor companies documented include American Motors (Jeep), Chrysler (Dodge, Plymouth), Datsun/Nissan, General Motors (Chevrolet, GMC trucks), International Harvester, Lincoln-Mercury, Mazda, Mitsubishi, Subaru, Toyota and White/Freightliner. Materials primarily in English but also Arabic, Chinese, Czech, Danish, Dutch, Flemish, French, German, Hungarian, Italian, Japanese, Norwegian, Portuguese, Russian and Spanish. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: General Files; Cars, Police/Emergency Vehicles, Taxicabs; Trucks, Vans, Industrial Vehicles; Competitive Brands; International Materials; Technical Literature.
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. It is headquartered in New York. JWT maintained an office in Detroit from 1909-1920 and reopened it in 1944.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. Detroit Office. Ford collateral literature was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as gifts in 1991-2008.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
J. Walter Thompson Company. Account files
J. Walter Thompson Company. Domestic advertisements collection
J. Walter Thompson Company. Detroit Office. Goldfarb Consultants Ford research reports
J. Walter Thompson Company. Detroit Office. Wallace W. Elton papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. International advertisements
J. Walter Thompson Company. Norman H. Strouse papers
Team Detroit Office records
Collection Overview
Collection includes catalogs, direct mailings, newsletters and magazines, owner's manuals, posters, sales incentive and sales training materials, service manuals, technical bulletins and other printed materials. Competitor companies documented include American Motors (Jeep), Chrysler (Dodge, Plymouth), Datsun/Nissan, General Motors (Chevrolet, GMC trucks), International Harvester, Lincoln-Mercury, Mazda, Mitsubishi, Subaru, Toyota and White/Freightliner. Materials primarily in English but also Arabic, Chinese, Czech, Danish, Dutch, Flemish, French, German, Hungarian, Italian, Japanese, Norwegian, Portuguese, Russian and Spanish. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising; Advertising -- United States -- History; Advertising agencies; Advertising agencies -- United States; Ford automobile -- Marketing -- History; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Ford Motor Company; Ford Motor Company. Lincoln-Mercury Division
- General Files, 1947-2005 and undated; 1
  - Accessories price lists, 1949 (Box GEN1)
  - Advance Product Highlights, 1979 (Box GEN1)
  - Announcement Action Plans, 1968 (Box GEN1)
  - Antique automobiles--Images with Fords of the 1930s, undated (Box GEN1)
  - Antique automobiles--Materials for Ford Truck Times article (Russ Anthony), 1970-1971 (Box GEN1)
  - Armchair Estimator--Price list, 1972 (Box GEN6)
  - Articles on exhaust emissions, pollution, unleaded gasoline, 1970-1971 (Box OV2)
  - Autolite Merchandising News, 1969-1970; 2 folders (Box GEN1)
  - Automotive News--Almanac Issues, 1959-1974 (Box GEN7)
  - Automotive News--Ford 75th Anniversary Issue, 1978 (Box GEN7)
  - Blue Oval Certified "Thumbie Awards", 2001 (Box GEN6)
  - Bottling industry, 1958-1963; 3 folders (Box GEN1)
  - Brochure--Cars and Trucks, 1997 (Box GEN1)
  - Calendar--Motorcraft, 1993 (Box GEN6)
  - Calendar--Predictions for the Next 1000 Years, 1983 (Box GEN6)
  - Champion Spark Plugs, 1973 (Box GEN1)
  - Chicago area body builders and equipment companies, 1958 (Box GEN1)
  - City congestion (Ford/American Trucking Association advocacy campaign), 1967 (Box GEN1)
  - Contests and prizes, 1966-1973; 2 folders (Box GEN1)
  - Contests and prizes--Including Punt, Pass and Kick, 1965-1973 (Box GEN6)
  - Contests and prizes--Including Punt, Pass and Kick, 1969 (Box OV3)
  - Contests and prizes--Including Punt, Pass and Kick, 1970-1973 (Box OV1)
  - Creating Effective Print Ads, 1995; 2 folders (Box GEN1)
  - Customer Relations News Bulletin, 1965 (Box GEN1)
  - Dealer Parts Salesman Reminder Calendars, 1949; 2 folders (Box GEN1)
  - Dealer Parts Salesman Reminder Calendars, 1949 (Box OV3)
  - Dealer sales promotions, 1947-1949 (Box GEN1)
  - Dealer sales promotions, 1954-1989; 3 folders (Box OV3)
  - Dealer Sales Tips, 1949 (Box GEN1)
  - Dealer showroom promotions, 1964-1971; 2 folders (Box GEN6)
  - Direct mail--Next Generation, undated (Box GEN1)
  - Direct mail designs, 1979 (Box GEN1)
  - Driver education, 1967-1969 (Box GEN1)
  - Driving Safety Home, undated (Box GEN1)
  - Facts Book--Accessories, 1987 (Box GEN1)
  - FDAF (Ford Dealer Advertising Fund) booklet, 1978 (Box GEN1)
  - FDAF Chairman's Guide Book, 1999 (Box GEN1)
  - Fleet Buyer's Kit, 1970 (Box GEN6)
  - Fleet management, 1967-1974 (Box GEN1)
  - Fleet Owner Warranty and Policy Review, 1961 (Box GEN1)
  - Ford.com (Internet sales), 1998 (Box GEN1)
  - Ford Around the World, 1993 (Box GEN1)
  - Ford Car and Truck Price Specifications, 1963-1964 (Box GEN1)
  - Ford Credit (English and Spanish), 1999 (Box GEN1)
  - Ford Dealer Advertising Kit--Official Clearance, 1989 (Box GEN6)
  - Ford Dealer Advertising Kit, 1987 (Box OV1)
  - Ford Dealer Advertising Planner, 1999 (Box GEN1)
  - Ford Dealer field report, 1950 (Box GEN1)
  - Ford Dealer Outdoor Poster Designs, 1995-1999 (Box GEN1)
  - Ford Dealer Toolbox, 2000 (Box GEN1)
  - Ford Dealer's Straight Talk, 1980 (Box GEN1)
  - Ford Facts, 1999 (Box GEN1)
  - Ford Global Partnership (JWTimes), 1997 (Box GEN1)
  - Ford Oval Owner's Manual, 2003 (Box GEN1)
  - Ford Owner newsletter, 1963 (Box GEN1)
  - Ford Salesman's 1966 Ford Prices (Box GEN1)
  - Ford/Thompson Times, 2001 (Box GEN1)
  - Ford Times, 1954 (Box GEN1)
  - Ford Times, 1955-1991; 19 folders (Box GEN2)
  - Ford World newsletter, 1973-1981 (Box OV1)
  - Frontline (sales magazine), 2002-2005; 2 folders (Box GEN2)
  - Gateway to the American Road of Tomorrow, undated (Box GEN2)
  - Good Bye Edsel!, 1985 (Box GEN2)
  - Great Goings On campaign, 1979 (Box GEN2)
  - Jennie Nash--A Day with Rosie (tribute to Rosie the Riveter), 2003 (Box GEN2)
  - Key Price and Product Comparisons--49-state, 1979 (Box GEN2)
  - Leasing, undated (Box GEN2)
  - Merchandising, 1965-1971 (Box GEN2)
  - Motor Trend--Car of the Year issue, 1964 (Box GEN2)
  - Motor Trend--How Ford Became #1, 1987 (Box GEN2)
  - Motorcraft spark plugs, 1978 (Box GEN2)
  - Motorsports accessories catalog, 1995 (Box GEN2)
  - My Ford, 2003 (Box GEN2)
  - NADA (National Automobile Dealers Association) Used Car Guide, 1978-1985 (Box GEN5)
  - National Dealer Council, 2004 (Box GEN2)
  - New England Journeys #6, 1958 (Box GEN2)
  - No Boundaries--Logo guidelines, 2001 (Box GEN2)
  - No Boundaries--Welcome to the Ford Family direct mail, 2003 (Box GEN2)
  - Parts and accessories, 1949 (Box GEN3)
  - Parts and accessories, 1948-1949 (Box GEN6)
  - Parts and accessories, 1947-1949 (Box OV1)
  - Performance products, 1968-1970 (Box GEN3)
  - Personal Portfolio--Cars and Trucks, 1999 (Box GEN8)
  - Posters, 1949-1970 and undated (Oversize-folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes: Demo Paydays sales incentive, with lunar landing tie-in, 1969; Ford Employee Tent Sale Days, 1965; "Ford Feel", 1949; Ford High Performance Parts, 1969; Ford Truck Baja 500, 1970; Free Wheeling/Built Ford Tough, undated; November Car Advertising Schedule, 1968; Used Car Classified Ad Writer promotion, 1949
  - Posters and advertising designs, cars and trucks, 1966-1971 (Box OV3)
  - Product information kit--Cars and trucks, 1998 (Box GEN6)
  - Promotion--CitiBank card, 1993 (Box GEN3)
  - Promotion--Gold Digger mail campaign aimed at housewives, 1970 (Box OV1)
  - Promotion--Olympic Edition Fords, 1980 (Box GEN6)
  - Promotion--Quiet Break Travel Award, 1970 (Box GEN3)
  - Promotion, new car introductions, 1951-1991 (Box OV1)
  - Road Report: Federal Highway Program (Ford/ATA publication), 1960 (Box GEN3)
  - Safety campaigns, 1949, 1966; 2 folders (Box GEN3)
  - Safety Headquarters sign, undated (Box GEN6)
  - Sales campaigns, 1954-1994; 8 folders (Box GEN3)
  - Sales programs feature in Detroit Free Press, 1966 (Box GEN6)
  - Sales campaigns--Dr. Seuss, 1949 (Box GEN3)
  - Sales campaigns--Go 70, 1970 (Box GEN3)
  - Sales campaigns--Go with the Going Thing, 1969 (Box GEN4)
  - Sales campaigns--Spring Zing, 1949 (Box GEN4)
  - Salesman's Guide to Direct Mail, 1969 (Box GEN6)
  - Salesmanship--Advertising: The Right Hand of Salesmanship, 1976 (Box GEN4)
  - Salesmanship--Double-knit blazers, 1976 (Box GEN4)
  - Salesmanship tips posters, 1970 (Box OV1)
  - Sarsaparilla song book for NADA convention, 1965 (Box GEN4)
  - Selling Plans for Ford Dealers, 1967 (Box GEN6)
  - Selling Strategy, 1972 (Box GEN4)
  - Selling the Product, undated (Box GEN4)
  - Service Depot directory, 1965 (Box GEN4)
  - Service Station and Independent Garage Operators Program, 1964 (Box GEN4)
  - Small Business Administration--Operating Hints for the Small Business Man, 1950s (Box GEN4)
  - Sponsorship--Punt, Pass and Kick competition, 1965-1975; 3 folders (Box GEN4)
  - Stickers, decals, hang tags, etc., undated (Box OV1)
  - Tax Saving Tips for the Independent Businessman, 1958 (Box GEN4)
  - The Best of the Times (compilation of Ford Times articles), 1977 (Box GEN4)
  - The Collection catalog, 2000 (Box GEN4)
  - Trailering with Ford, undated (Box GEN4)
  - Transcribed radio spots, 1971 (Box GEN4)
  - Want List for Genuine Ford Parts (images of hoods and grilles 1936-1949) (Box GEN4)
  - Warranty Facts booklet, 1974 (Box GEN4)
  - Wasted: $3 Billions Yearly: A Positive Program of Highway Building (Automobile Manufacturers Association), 1953 (Box GEN4)
  - Who Cares When the Construction Stops? (Ford/ATA), 1967 (Box GEN4)
  - Your Car and Clean Air, 1970 (Box GEN4)
- Cars, Police/Emergency Vehicles, Taxicabs, 1941-2007 and undated; 2
  - Accessories catalog, 1955 (Box CAR1)
  - Brochures, catalogs, etc., 1941-1969; 9 folders (Box CAR5)
  - Brochures, catalogs, etc., 1946-1983; 38 folders (Box CAR1)
  - Brochures, catalogs, etc., 1949-1972; 2 folders (Box OV3)
  - Brochures, catalogs, etc., 1971-1986; 6 folders (Box CAR6)
  - Brochures, catalogs, etc., 1984-2007; 24 folders (Box CAR2)
  - Brochures, catalogs, etc., 1987-1990; 3 folders (Box CAR7)
  - Brochures, catalogs, etc., 1991-2005; 3 folders (Box CAR8)
  - Brochures, catalogs, etc.--Anglia, 1960 (Box CAR2)
  - Brochures, catalogs, etc.--Cortina, 1969-1971; 4 folders (Box CAR2)
  - Brochures, catalogs, etc.--Cortina, 1969 (Box CAR8)
  - Brochures, catalogs, etc.--Country Squire, 1949 (Box CAR8)
  - Brochures, catalogs, etc.--Mustang, 1964-1982; 4 folders (Box CAR2)
  - Brochures, catalogs, etc.--Mustang, 1964-1991 (Box CAR8)
  - Brochures, catalogs, etc.--Mustang, 1983-2006; 3 folders (Box CAR3)
  - Brochures, catalogs, etc.--Mustang 30th anniversary poster "Time Machine", 1994 (Box OV3)
  - Brochures, catalogs, etc.--Mustang first birthday, 1965 (Box OV1)
  - Brochures, catalogs, etc.--Parts and accessories, 1949-1950; 2 folders (Box CAR3)
  - Brochures, catalogs, etc.--Sales, 1970-1974 (Box CAR3)
  - Brochures, catalogs, etc.--Spanish language, 1983-1999; 2 folders (Box CAR3)
  - Brochures, catalogs, etc.--Spanish language, 1986 (Box CAR8)
  - Brochures, catalogs, etc.--Thunderbird, 1955-2005; 8 folders (Box CAR3)
  - Brochures, catalogs, etc.--Thunderbird, 1957-1965; 2 folders (Box CAR8)
  - Brochures, catalogs, etc.--Thunderbird, 1958 (Box OV3)
  - Brochures, catalogs, etc.--Thunderbird, 1958-1973 (Box OV1)
  - Brochures, catalogs, etc.--Thunderbird, 1966-1991; 5 folders (Box CAR9)
  - Buyer's Digest of New Car Facts, 1959-1979; 4 folders (Box CAR3)
  - Car Buying Made Easier, 1979 (Box CAR3)
  - Car Facts Sheet, 1975 (Box CAR9)
  - Connecta (electric concept car), undated (Box CAR3)
  - Connecta/Ecostar electric vehicles, undated (Box CAR3)
  - Contour media launch plan, 1995 (Box CAR3)
  - Direct mail, 1966-1969; 5 folders (Box CAR3)
  - Fashion Academy award, 1949 (Box CAR3)
  - Fleet Guide Preview, 2005 (Box CAR3)
  - Fleet Owner Handbook, 1962 (Box CAR3)
  - Flex Fuel Taurus, 1993-1994; 2 folders (Box CAR3)
  - Focus "Fanfare" binder, 1999 (Box CAR3)
  - Futura announcement, 1977 (Box CAR9)
  - Hot New Dishes on Ford's Giant Menu, 1963 (Box CAR3)
  - Lease, rental programs, 1965-1968 (Box CAR9)
  - Motor Trend Car of the Year, 1964 (Box CAR3)
  - Mustanger newsletter, 1967-1969 (Box CAR3)
  - Owner's manual, 1956-1957; 2 folders (Box CAR3)
  - Parts, accessories, service, 1949 (Box CAR3)
  - Performance Corner, 1970 (Box CAR9)
  - Performance Days mail campaign, undated (Box CAR3)
  - Peanuts campaign, 1960 (Box CAR3)
  - Police, emergency packages, 1949-1998; 6 folders (Box CAR3)
  - Police, emergency packages, 1957-1996 (Box CAR9)
  - Price lists, 1960-1961 (Box CAR3)
  - Promotions, 1966-1978; 2 folders (Box CAR3)
  - Promotions--Contests, 1964-1969; 2 folders (Box CAR3)
  - Promotions--Diamond Jubilee, 1978 (Box CAR3)
  - Promotions--Ford Sports Club (Cortina), 1968 (Box CAR3)
  - Promotions--Four Seasons Outdoor Association, 1970 (Box CAR3)
  - Promotions--Topps trading card booklet, 1998 (Box CAR3)
  - Promotions--Wild Wild Coloring Book, 1979 (Box CAR3)
  - Quick Facts, 1947-1949 (Box CAR4)
  - Radio spot scripts, 1949 (Box CAR4)
  - Road and Track Enthusiasts' Guide, 1999 (Box CAR4)
  - Safety campaigns, 1949 (Box CAR4)
  - Sales literature--Using Your Ford Mileage-Maker Six Demonstration Kit, 1958 (Box CAR4)
  - Sales promotion--Going Thing Fling, 1969 (Box CAR9)
  - Sales promotion--New Car Introduction, 1979 (Box CAR9)
  - Salesmanship--Get a Corner on Performance, 1969 (Box CAR4)
  - Taxi service packages, 1949-1974; 4 folders (Box CAR4)
  - Taxi service packages, 1957-1969 (Box CAR9)
  - Trustmark postcard, undated (Box CAR4)
  - Value Book, 1969 (Box CAR4)
  - World Car program, 1981 (Box CAR4)
- Trucks, Vans, Industrial Vehicles, 1941-2007 and undated; 3
  - 58 Ford Truck Product Knowledge quiz contest promotion, 1958 (Box T1)
  - Accessories catalog, 1964-1978; 3 folders (Box T1)
  - Advertising, dealer promotions, 1962-1971 (Box OV2)
  - Advertising proof binder, 1975 (Box T1)
  - Ambulance, 1969 (Box T1)
  - Big Fleets Keep Buying Ford Tractors, 1964 (Box T1)
  - Big Rigs Rolling, 1960 (Box T1)
  - Bottling industry, 1946-1967; 2 folders (Box T1)
  - Brochures, catalogs, etc., 1945-1967; 29 folders (Box T1)
  - Brochures, catalogs, etc., 1951-1958; 2 folders (Box OV3)
  - Brochures, catalogs, etc. (some Spanish in 1985 folder), 1953-1985; 8 folders (Box T11)
  - Brochures, catalogs, etc., 1967-1979; 30 folders (Box T2)
  - Brochures, catalogs, etc., 1980-1995; 27 folders (Box T3)
  - Brochures, catalogs, etc., 1985-1989; 5 folders (Box T12)
  - Brochures, catalogs, etc., 1990-2004; 3 folders (Box T13)
  - Brochures, catalogs, etc., 1995-2007; 22 folders (Box T4)
  - Brochures, catalogs, etc.--Engines, 1965 (Box T4)
  - Brochures, catalogs, etc.--Escape, 2001 (Box T4)
  - Brochures, catalogs, etc.--Harley Davidson edition, 2004 (Box T13)
  - Brochures, catalogs, etc.--Spanish language, 1983-1992; 2 folders (Box T4)
  - Brochures, catalogs, etc.--Tractors and industrial, 1980s (Box T4)
  - Brochures, catalogs, etc.--"Triple Economy" campaign, 1955 (Box OV2)
  - Building Truck Sales Through Advertising and Sales Promotion, undated (Box T4)
  - Building Truck Service Volume and Profit, undated (Box T4)
  - Careers in Trucking Companies, 1973-1974 (Box T4)
  - Clues (To Successful Truck Operations), 1952-1954; 3 folders (Box T4)
  - Clues (To Successful Truck Operations), 1954-1966; 15 folders (Box T5)
  - Comparison guides, 1961 (Box T5)
  - Competitive Selling Assistant, 2000 (Box T5)
  - Concrete Mixer Application Data Books (truck selection guides), 1959-1960 (Box T5)
  - Confidential Pocket Facts, 1957 (Box T5)
  - Construction--Tractors, 1968 (Box T5)
  - Courier dealer advertising material, 1972 (Box T13)
  - Daily Expense and Record Books (truck driver logs), 1959-1965 (Box T5)
  - Dealer advertising materials, 1974 (Box T5)
  - Designed for the Construction Industry, 1970 (Box T5)
  - Detailed Component Descriptions: W-WT-9000 Diesels, 1973 (Box T5)
  - Diesel Engine Operating and Maintenance Instructions, 1963 (Box T5)
  - Diesel models, 1961-1962 (Box T5)
  - Direct mail, 1951-1963; 4 folders (Box T13)
  - Direct mail, 1952-1963; 15 folders (Box T5)
  - Direct mail, 1964-1974; 2 folders (Box T14)
  - Direct mail, 1964-2000; 29 folders (Box T6)
  - Direct Route to Double Savings coupon book, 1970 (Box T6)
  - Dump Body Specification Guide, 1970 (Box T6)
  - Eaton--Fuller transmission parts, undated (Box T6)
  - Eaton--Truck Topics newsletter, 1976-1977 (Box T6)
  - Econoline (includes testimonial mailings), 1960-1967; 2 folders (Box T6)
  - Engines, 1959-1979; 2 folders (Box T6)
  - Experimental gas turbine truck (Big Red), 1964-1965 (Box T6)
  - F-150 campaign clipping, 2003 (Box T6)
  - Farm, ranch use, tractors, 1958-1994; 5 folders (Box T6)
  - Fashions for Women campaign, 1966 (Box T6)
  - Federal Highway Program (Ford/ATA advocacy campaign), 1970 (Box T6)
  - Final Results 50- Million Mile Ford Truck Economy Run, 1951 (Box OV2)
  - Fire and rescue--Blitz Buggy, 1958 (Box T6)
  - Fire and rescue--Boardman, 1965 (Box T6)
  - Fire and rescue--Darley, 1965 (Box T6)
  - Fire and rescue--Gerstenslager, 1965 (Box T7)
  - Fire and rescue--Hahn Motors, 1966 (Box T7)
  - Fire and rescue--Howe, 1965 (Box T7)
  - Fire and rescue--John Bean, 1965 (Box T7)
  - Fire and rescue--Miscellaneous (includes Ford publications), 1953-1975; 3 folders (Box T7)
  - Fire and rescue--Peter Pirsch and Sons, 1965 (Box T7)
  - Fire and rescue--Pierce, 1963 (Box T7)
  - Fire and rescue--Seagrave, 1965 (Box T7)
  - Fire and rescue--Snorkel/Pitman, 1965 (Box T7)
  - Fire and rescue--Ward/La France, 1966 (Box T7)
  - Fire and rescue--Young, 1965 (Box T7)
  - Fleet management, 1965-1970 (Box T14)
  - Fleet management, 1968-1971; 2 folders (Box T7)
  - Fleet Owner Handbook, 1961 (Box T14)
  - Fleet truck finance plan, 1962 (Box T7)
  - Ford/ATA advertising campaign, 1966 (Box OV2)
  - Ford Dealer Newspaper Advertising Ideas, 1969-1974; 2 folders (Box T7)
  - Ford Explorer Owner's Club, 1998 (Box T14)
  - Ford F-100 Built Like the Big Ones, 1963 (Box T7)
  - Ford Heavy Truck Advisory Committee, 1968 (Box T7)
  - Ford Spring Tandem Sales Contest, 1960 (Box T7)
  - Ford Tandem Trucks, 1963 (Box T7)
  - Ford Truck 100,000 Mile Reliability Run, 1963 (Box T7)
  - Ford Truck Product Improvements, 1970-1971 (Box T7)
  - Ford Truck Times, 1948-1975; 16 folders (Box T7)
  - Ford Trucks for the Construction Industry, 1961-1968; 2 folders (Box T7)
  - Four Seasons Trails, 1970-1971 (Box T7)
  - Guide to Cutting Truck Costs, 1962 (Box T7)
  - Guides to truck selection for the construction industry, 1956-1961 (Box T7)
  - Handy Guide for the One-Truck Fleet Owner, 1972 (Box T7)
  - Hard Runners: On the Road with America's Long-Haul Truckers (Bryan Di Salvatore, Elma Garcia), 1988 (Box T14)
  - Heavy-duty trucks, 1962-1966 (Box T7)
  - Heavy-duty testimonials, 1962 (Box T7)
  - Heavy truck press information, 1966 (Box T7)
  - Hi-Lo newsletter, 1952 (Box T7)
  - Horses to Horsepower, 1948 (Box T7)
  - Hot Tips for Selling Ford Tandems, 1960 (Box T7)
  - Hybrid Escape, 2005 (Box T7)
  - Industrial/Agricultural Tractors and Equipment, 1968 (Box T7)
  - Kentucky Truck Plant, 1992 (Box T14)
  - Leasing, 1995 (Box T7)
  - Lifelines: How Trucks Serve America (Automobile Manufacturers Association), 1965 (Box T7)
  - Light-duty trucks, 1964-1971 (Box T7)
  - Light Truck Pocket Facts, 1979 (Box T8)
  - Light Truck Selling Manual, 1982 (Box T8)
  - Louisville Story, 1965 (Box T14)
  - Louisville Truck Plant, 1996 (Box T8)
  - Merchandising--Built Ford Tough Insider, 2000 (Box T8)
  - More Truck for the Money, 1954 (Box T8)
  - No Boundaries campaign, 2000 (Box T8)
  - Operator's manuals, 1958-1974; 10 folders (Box T8)
  - Owner's guides, 1980 (Box T8)
  - Owner's manual, 1957-1977; 5 folders (Box T8)
  - Owner's manual--Bronco, 1968 (Box T8)
  - Parcel delivery trucks, 1958 (Box T8)
  - Parts, accessories, service, 1949 (Box T8)
  - Paying Your Truck Sales Manpower, 1957 (Box T8)
  - Price list, 1980 (Box T8)
  - Production schedules, literature, etc., 1967 (Box T8)
  - Profitable Used Truck Merchandising, 1958 (Box T8)
  - Promotion--Island Takeover, 1969 (Box T8)
  - Promotion--Snowplow attachments, 1968-1969 (Box T8)
  - Ranchero mounted advertisement, 1966 (Box T14)
  - Quick Facts, 1958-1968; 3 folders (Box T8)
  - Recreational vehicles, campers, 1962-1971; 5 folders (Box T8)
  - Recreational vehicles, campers, 1965-1973; 4 folders (Box T9)
  - Recreational vehicles, campers, 1973 (Box T14)
  - Safety campaigns--Motor Carrier Safety Regulations (Interstate Commerce Commission), 1941 (Box T9)
  - Safety campaigns--Safe Winter Driving Facts, 1953 (Box T9)
  - Safety campaigns--Vehicle manual, 1966 (Box T9)
  - Sales and service directories, 1958-1965; 3 folders (Box T9)
  - Sales campaigns, 1965-1973; 2 folders (Box T9)
  - Sales literature--Presenting the Product, 1961 (Box T9)
  - Sales Training Newsflash, 1976 (Box T9)
  - Salesman flip book--Get Set to Blast Off Into 1961 (Box T9)
  - Sport Trac Guide to Life, 2007 (Box T10)
  - Suggested retail prices, 1978 (Box T10)
  - Suspension photographs, 1960 (Box T10)
  - Tandem trucks, 1964 (Box T10)
  - Tax Saving Tips for the Independent Businessman, 1958 (Box T10)
  - The ABC of Ford Truck Selling, 1946 (Box T14)
  - The Big Ones with Better Ideas, 1969 (Box T10)
  - Tilt Cab Tandem Series, 1960 (Box T10)
  - Tractor selection guides, 1962-1967 (Box T10)
  - Truck sales recognition programs, 1968-1971 (Box T10)
  - Trucks for the Bell System, 1954 (Box T10)
  - W-Series Salesman Guide, 1966; 2 folders (Box T10)
  - Why '62 Ford Trucks Are More Service-Free, 1962 (Box T10)
- Competitive Brands, 1948-2004 and undated; 4
  - Acura, 1986 (Box COM1)
  - American Motors--American Motors News Illustrated, 1964-1965 (Box COM8)
  - American Motors--Americana Magazine, 1965-1967 (Box COM1)
  - American Motors--Eagle, 1993 (Box COM1)
  - American Motors--Jeep, 1959-1987; 6 folders (Box COM1)
  - American Motors--Jeep, 1967-1986; 4 folders (Box COM8)
  - American Motors--Jeep direct mail, 1966-1975; 3 folders (Box COM1)
  - American Motors--Jeep print advertising and miscellaneous, 1962-1980 (Box COM1)
  - American Motors--Jeep product information and data book, 1985 (Box COM1)
  - American Motors--Jeep/Renault, 1981-1985; 3 folders (Box COM1)
  - Austin (trucks, U.K.), 1950s (Box COM1)
  - Autocar (White), 1955-1974; 3 folders (Box COM1)
  - BMW motorcycles, 1998 (Box COM1)
  - Brockway (Mack), 1968-1975; 2 folders (Box COM1)
  - Buick, 1964, 1995 (Box COM1)